-[eagle screeching]
-[whimpering]
[King] What is this creature?
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
TAKING STOCK X AND X TAKING ACTION
[birds chirping]
[narrator] One day remains
before the sorting,
Hey. Good morning.
Up already? It's kinda early.
[Killua] Nineteen hours
till midnight on sorting day.
We make our move tonight.
Right. Let's do one final check.
[map beeping]
Once we're in, Gon and I will head up
the central stairway to the throne room.
If you find her, escape without us.
You got it.
If the King and his three Royal Guards
You're really hung up on that, aren't you?
Yeah, what are the chances?
It's pretty unlikely.
[Killua] It is, but you've gotta admit
unlikely things happen all the time.
We did a bunch of research
on the enemy's behavior
and used it to decide when to attack.
When you think you know
exactly where and when
you can expect someone to be,
more often than not,
that's when the unexpected happens.
It was pretty common in my old job.
We don't have that luxury.
As soon as we make a move,
there's no turning back.
We need to plan for every scenario
and decide what we would do.
[Killua] They might not be
in the throne room,
but if they're still in the palace,
it's okay.
Pitou's En is enough to cover the palace,
the surrounding courtyards, and then some.
So as soon as we enter,
we need to see if we can sense
that creepy aura anywhere close by.
That'll tell us
whether or not they're there.
Then we just follow that aura
to where it feels the most dense.
Oh!
Right. That's what I can't figure out.
The Royal Guard
never leaves the King's side,
so if Pouf was there,
I'm positive the other two
were in the palace with the King too.
Well, then we should ask Colt himself.
[Killua] Yeah.
[Colt] I'd guess Pitou was giving
someone medical attention.
[Killua over phone] What?
I did tell you that Pitou was the one
who repaired Kite, didn't I?
In hindsight, I don't believe
Pitou used En during that time.
Healing must require
a great deal of concentration.
who would have had the skills
to injure them?
Good question.
An internal dispute?
Maybe the King injured
one of the Royal Guards for some reason?
No. No, that's impossible.
and that's never gonna happen.
But I guess the bigger question now is
who was it that injured the King?
The Royal Guard would never harm him,
and you could rule out the underlings too.
They'd never so much as
put a scratch on him.
[Gon over phone] You're right,
and that's why we're pretty sure…
He injured himself?
Wait. How could that have happened?
We don't know what's going on here yet,
but it's all we've got.
-[Ikalgo grunts]
-[Killua] Mmm-hmm.
[line disconnects]
but that chance
wouldn't have been possible
under normal circumstances.
It looks like their march
has begun at last.
Ten hours until midnight,
when the sorting starts.
five million humans
will fill the palace grounds.
They may try
to use the celebration as a cover
is that the King may somehow
be spirited away beyond our reach.
Let's just say that one of them
has the ability to teleport objects.
The King's been irritated enough with us
because of how close
we've been covering him as it is.
Then we guard him secretly
without his knowledge.
The only problem with that
is that we need someone
close enough to monitor his surroundings
Meow all of the enemy presences
have completely disappeared.
And I can't sense
any residual aura from them whatsoever.
They must be using Zetsu
to hide amongst the marching humans.
Hey. What's up?
[Knuckle] There are so many people.
Looks like they had
about a hundred per building.
They all must have been packed inside.
Then if we all conceal our presences,
they'll be forced to assume that
we're hiding somewhere among the citizens.
Do you think there's any chance
they'll decide
to cancel the march altogether?
No. No way.
That would mean delaying
or even canceling the entire celebration,
which would imply the King
had accepted defeat and compromised.
So the celebration is gonna begin
as scheduled, tomorrow at 3:00 p.m. sharp,
and there's not a damn thing
we can do to stop it.
[Neferpitou sighs]
Once the humans started to move,
my puppets couldn't
tell them apart anymore.
Well, what do you think?
Should I recall them right meow?
No. Giving the enemy free rein
would be simply ridiculous.
[groans]
[Morel] It's just like we thought.
The Nen puppets have joined the march.
We'll have to avoid the front entrances
due to heightened security,
So what? Are you getting scared?
That's absurd. I just don't want
to be caught off guard, okay?
Waiting by the entrances
for the right moment
since the Ants can pick up on the signal.
you shouldn't take their security net
too lightly.
-[Knov] I'll handle it.
-Huh?
[Knov] I'm the only one among us
who can enter and exit these rooms
whenever I please.
I'll keep you all informed.
For now, you should rest here.
You sure you'll be okay?
I'm just keeping watch.
I can't imagine that'll be a problem.
I'll be close,
but right outside of Pitou's En range, so…
That's exactly what Kite ran into.
Yeah, he probably did that deliberately.
Not a single one of you
can strike fear in me like they do.
I won't take any risks…
ever again.
Any person who leaves their line
will be shot on sight.
Move out!
Pitou.
You knew that Komugi was being attacked,
did you not?
Yes. I was monitoring the area with En.
However, I saw no threat to you, sire,
so I ignored it.
From this point on,
you'll keep an eye on Komugi as well
and deal with any threats at once.
Yes, as you wish.
heading toward the King…
just like ants.
No, lemmings.
Wait a second. What is that?
Every one of them
looks completely vacant, dazed.
Those scales must have a hypnotic effect.
Stay in line as you advance!
Do not leave this line!
Once you're in position,
wait for orders, and don't move!
[Knov] Simple orders repeated on a loop
while tanks roll in the background
can easily seep into a mind
exhausted from hours of marching.
obedient till the end,
when it's their turn.
[snoring]
[Morel] Hypnosis? I see.
-Huh?
-We won't have to worry
about the whole crowd
flying into a total panic
if the battle
starts to get out of control.
This is a really big deal.
And assuming that over half of the people
will be in place at midnight
waiting for the sorting process
to get started,
Now we can fight all we want.
[grunts]
[Shoot] They both look so calm.
It's like he's overflowing
with confidence.
But I can't help but wonder,
why is it that,
now and then, he seems so sad?
Out of everyone here,
I'm the one suffering
from the most anxiety.
The fate of humanity
rests on my shoulders.
[Knuckle] Colt is a good guy.
Meleoron and Ikalgo,
they both have good hearts.
It doesn't matter
if they're humans or Ants.
Everyone has a heart.
That has to be true.
by defeating that Ant.
[Killua] He's fired up.
All these battles are taking their toll.
On a scale of 1 to 100, I'm about 40.
No, 35.
Can't cry about it now.
With Knov out, I'm the only one left.
I'd hoped to fight at full strength,
but it's much easier
to accept my fate this way.
[Knov] I'm sorry, Morel, everyone.
[shudders] But I…
I can't face them again.
I'll go check on the palace.
[Meleoron] So two minutes
is about the longest I can hold my breath.
Given how tense I'll be,
my limit will probably be half that
at best.
It's fine.
A minute is more than enough time.
Thank you for that, Killua.
[King] I am King.
But who am I, really?
Our time's up. Let's go.
[Gon] Palm.
[narrator] Ten minutes remain
until they enter the palace.
[singer singing in Japanese]